Hi, and welcome to the first video
in this spreadsheet software unit.
So far during the course, you will
have seen me use information contained
within a spreadsheet to enhance
the meaning and appearance of a
presentation and a Word document.
For example, with the table and the chart
in the presentation unit and also the mail
merge content in the word processing unit.
In this unit, you're going to learn
how you can add information into
Excel and carry out a range of tasks
and functions on that information.
The first thing we need to look at is
the way Excel structures information.
So I'm going to just open Excel
and once that has opened I will
select a new blank document.
So if I go to New and I have blank
workbook here, so within Excel, each
spreadsheet is called a workbook.
And within the workbook,
you will have worksheets.
So we'll just come to that at the
moment, but you can also see that
you have a range of templates.
It's very similar to Word and PowerPoint
that for whatever tasks that you need
to complete, there's probably a template
that will assist you with this, but I'm
just going to click on blank workbook.
And once that opens a blank
workbook, you can see the main page.
So very similar to Word, PowerPoint
all of your toolbars are along the top,
the tabs there, there are some slight
differences such as formulas and data.
There are some slight differences to
each of the toolbars in relation to
the tools that are on those toolbars.
They're specific to
Excel in this instance.
And as you can see on the page, you
have a number of columns and rows
and at the top of each column, you
have a letter and alongside each
of the rows you have a number.
The reason for this is that
Excel uses cell referencing to
carry out functions and tasks.
So if you have information in a
specific cell, that is how Excel will
identify that cell and the information
in it and what needs to be done to it.
So I may have information in E7 and F7
that I need to add up and display in G7.
So I would use a formula
within there to identify the
information in those two cells.
And it would provide me with
the output in that cell.
In addition to that, Excel also
structures information in worksheets.
And the first one is sheet 1 which is the
very first sheet that opens by default.
And it may be a case that I'm
creating something that needs multiple
worksheets, so it could be a year
planner or a budget for a year.
So I would need 12 worksheets.
So to add additional worksheets, I
would just click on the plus sign and
that will add the sheets and until
I'm satisfied that I have sufficient.
So just for an example, I've got seven
sheets and if this was a year planner,
I would need to change the name so I
could identify that that was January.
So I just double click on that and
I can type in the text January,
again, just double click on that
and February and so on and so forth.
So that's basically the primary structure
and the way information is displayed
within Excel and on the next video we'll
input information into the spreadsheet.
So you can see how you can format that
and carry out formulas and functions.